SAM RAHA

Front End Developer

07842602888

V Leeds. UK

sam.raha@hotmail.co.uk

www.samraha.com

PROFILE

After a first-class Honours Degree in Finance and a 3-year career in the procurement industry, I've decided to change direction and follow my passion for web development. I've enjoyed learning full stack development for the past 8 months through online courses and articles, books and Meetup groups to improve myself to the best of my ability, and it is now my main focus to contribute to and learn from a professional team of developers to advance my career to the next level.

EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer

Freelance 08/2019 - Present https://samraha.github.io/TheLooseCut/

<u>Landing Page – The Loose Cut:</u> (ongoing)

- Designed and coded a front-end static landing page with multi device compatibility for an official Leeds and Reading Festival band using HTML, CSS & JavaScript.
- Gained exposure to domain hosting, client interaction/ communication and improved understanding of agile development phases such as implementing customer feedback queries until all functionalities are tested and complete.
- The website acts as a vehicle for promotion and digital exposure through features such as animated social media buttons, a link to the merch website, and a background dynamically showcasing previous events.

Full Stack Developer

Personal Projects 01/2019 - 08/2019samraha.com/#portfolio

- Face Detector App: A full stack application that uses a machine learning API to recognise faces. Created with ReactJS, CSS, NodeJS, PostgreSQL & Clarifai API and deployed with Heroku. It also utilises a sign in system secured with Bcrypt password hashing. The creation of this application greatly improved my understanding of how the front and back-end of a complex dynamic app are connected via a server.
- **Portfolio Website:** a static front-end website that showcases my portfolio and skills. Created with HTML, CSS, jQuery & JavaScript. Gained exposure to domain hosting and utilising advanced CSS features such as CSS Grid, Flexbox, Bootstrap, pseudo elements and *media queries* to design a multi browser supported and fully responsive website.
- **Gatsby Blog:** A personal blog to share developer resources. Created with GatsbyJS, ReactJS, GraphQL & CSS and deployed via Netlify. This project taught me how to utilise one of the fastest static site generator frameworks to build a Progressive Web App with performance in mind.
- Robofriends: A fun front-end React app that displays a friends list with a search function. Created with ReactJS, CSS & Robohash API. This project exposed me to the difference between developing vanilla JavaScript and React applications through component management.

Senior Buyer

07/2017 - 05/2019 **Dragados** https://tinyurl.com/BSCUDG London, UK £600m London Underground Bank Station Capacity Upgrade Project:

- Automated non value added activities that existed in day to day roles within the department using VBA and Python programming, i.e. using CSV parsing tools to mass populate purchase order logs from multiple excel files.
- Serving as the direct report for the Apprentice Buyer in the team. This developed my emotional intelligence, active listening, development training skills and the necessary skills required to cater to staff with special needs, i.e. breaking down the work into smaller, more manageable chunks and avoiding multi-tasking to stay focused.
- Acting as project manager for the implementation of a new asset management software by utilising Kanban for project completion.

SKILLS

HTML5 CSS3 JavaScript ¡Query ReactJS Bootstrap Photoshop CS6 NodeJS PostgreSQL Python Git Netlify Heroku GatsbyJS

EDUCATION

The Complete Web Developer in 2019 - Full Stack Development

Udemy- Zero to Mastery 01/2019 - 03/2019 Studying topics such as: How the Internet Works, History Of The Web, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript ES6/ES7/ES8, React, Redux, Git + Github, Node.js, Express.js, NPM, PostgresSQL, SQL & Python.

First Class Accounting and Finance BSc (Hons) Degree

University of Brighton 09/2013 - 05/2017

ACHIEVEMENTS

Black Belt in Taekwondo

Achieved at 10 y/o, teaching me discipline and leadership skills.

Tough Mudder (Full Challenge)

Awesome team bonding activity that raised money for charity.

Finalists in the Brighton University Football League

Captained/ managed a football team comprised of friends and university peers that achieved 2nd place out of 24 teams.